Guide to the Franklin Toker Papers, 1964-2017 UA.90.F108
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Franklin Toker Papers
1964-2017
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Toker, Franklin
UA.90.F108
76.25 Linear Feet (61 boxes)
Franklin Toker is an architectural historian, professor, and author best known for his work on Frank Lloyd Wright's Fallingwater, Pittsburgh architecture, and the Duomo in Florence, Italy. This collection includes materials pertaining to Toker's research, publications, and teaching and professional activities.
Scope and Content Notes
The Franklin Toker Papers span the entire career of the architect, author, and professor. Much of the collection consists of research and drafts of several of his publications, including The Church of Notre-Dame in Montreal, Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait, Fallingwater Rising, and his multi-volume Florence Duomo Project. Also included are research files on the Carnegie Museum of Natural History's Hall of Architecture, general research files, course materials, and professional correspondence.
Biography
Franklin Toker was born in 1944 in Montreal, Canada. He studied Fine Arts at McGill University, completing his undergraduate studies in 1964. He next attended Oberlin College, receiving a Master's degree in History of Art in 1966 and his Ph.D. in Fine Arts from Harvard University in 1973. After earning his doctorate, Toker taught at several schools, including Boston School of Architecture, Dartmouth College in Florence, and Carnegie Mellon University, before ultimately arriving at the University of Pittsburgh as a professor of History of Art and Architecture in 1987. He also lectured abroad in countries like Italy, Canada, India, and Japan.
Toker has written eleven books, most notably his volumes on the Florence Duomo Project, Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait, Fallingwater Rising, and The Church of Notre-Dame in Montreal. His work on the Florence Duomo Project is made up of 4 books: On Holy Ground: Liturgy, Architecture, and Urbanism in the Cathedral and the Streets of Medieval Florence; Archaeological Campaigns below the Florence Duomo and Baptistry; Reconstructing the Cathedral and Baptistry of Florence in Late Antiquity and the Middle Ages; and When Stones Speak: The Florence Duomo Excavations in the Light of History. In the process of writing these books, Toker participated in two archaeological digs in Florence, one of them being at the famous Cathedral of Saint Maria del Fiore. Toker also took an interest in architecture local to him in Pittsburgh. He completed extensive research on Pittsburgh neighborhoods, buildings, and industries, which contributed to several of his books.
Over the course of his career, Toker received many awards and accolades. Toker was the president of the Society of Architectural Historians in 1992. He was a member of the Institute for Advanced Study at Princeton University, as well as a Guggenheim and National Endowment for the Humanities fellow. For his writing, Toker received the Alice Davis Hitchcock Award of the Society of Architectural Historians in 1970, and the Porter Prize of the College Art Association in 1978. In November 2017, Toker was named a Distinguished Professor of the University of Pittsburgh.
Related Material
Israel Heritage Room Committee Collection, 1929-2013, UA.40.13, University Archives, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Franklin Toker in May 2018.
Historic buildings -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Architecture -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Faculty papers; University of Pittsburgh; Notre-Dame de Montreal (Church); Santa Maria del Fiore (Cathedral: Florence, Italy) -- History; Fallingwater (Pa.); Toker, Franklin
- The Church of Notre-Dame in Montreal, 1964-1992; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series consists of research conducted by Dr. Frank Toker for his 1970 book The Church of Notre-Dame in Montreal: An Architectural History. A second edition of the book was published in 1991. The research consists of correspondence regarding the book and building, lectures given by Dr. Toker about the Cathedral, photographs of the building used in the book, and other articles about the Cathedral and its construction. This series also contains a copy of the 1970 edition of the completed book.
  - Notes for Research on Notre-Dame, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Notre-Dame Notes, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Notre-Dame Cathedral Montreal Research (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
  - Notre-Dame: Ongoing and Future Research (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Montreal Research (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Canada Research (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Facultee De Lettres (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Cathedral Photos (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cathedral Lecture, Articles, and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notre-Dame De Montreal Article (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Church of Notre-Dame in Montreal: An Architectural History (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait, 1986-2008; II.
  This series contains research files and drafts of Dr. Toker's 1986 book, Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait, and its 2009 revised edition, Pittsburgh: A New Portrait. The books analyze the urban setting of Pittsburgh and the ways in which Pittsburgh has changed over time. These changes are reflected in research files about Pittsburgh and western Pennsylvania buildings, neighborhoods, and industries.
  - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait, 1986 Edition, 1986-1995; 1.
    This subseries mainly contains research on Pittsburgh buildings, neighborhoods, and industry. It also contains drafts of the first edition of the book at various stages.
    - Buildings, Structures and Locations, 1986-1995
      - A. Kahn's Chrysler Sales Building Research (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Alcoa Research (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Allegheny Cemetery Research (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Allegheny Commons East Research (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail Research (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Allegheny General Hospital Research (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Allegheny Landing Park Research (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Allegheny Observatory Research (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Allegheny Widows' Home Research (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Alpha Terrace Research (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - American Wind Symphony Barge Research (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Anderson Street Research (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Arsenal Research (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - August Wilson Center Research (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Bank Library Research (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Baywood Research (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Bedford School Research (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Bedford Square Research (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Beech Avenue Allegheny West Research (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Bell Telephone Research (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Bellefield Dwellings Research (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Benedum–Trees Building Research (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Buhl Planetarium Research (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Burke Building Research (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Calliope House Research (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Calvary Methodist Episcopal Church Research (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - CAPA (Creative and Performing Arts) Research (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Cap. 1 Supplemental Information (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Carnegie Hall, North Side Research (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Carnegie Institute and Library Research (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Carnegie Mellon University Research (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Carnegie Mellon University Robotics Center Research (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Carnegie Science Center Research (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Cedar Avenue Research (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Chatham Village Research (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - City-County Building Research (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Clark Building Research (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Clayton Research (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - CNG Tower Research (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Community College of Allegheny County Research (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Convention Center Research (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Cornerstone Baptist Church Research (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Dollar Bank Research (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Duquesne Club Research (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - East Carson Street Research (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - East Liberty and Highland Park Research (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - East Liberty Presbyterian Church Research (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - East Liberty Research (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Eberhardt-Ober Brewery Research (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Edgewood Railroad Station Research (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Emmanuel Episcopal Church Research (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Equibank Research (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Fifth Avenue Buildings Research (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Fifth Avenue Place Research (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - First Baptist Research (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - First Presbyterian Church Research (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - First Side Building Research (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Fort Duquesne Boulevard Buildings Research (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Fort Pitt Research (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Fourth Avenue Banking Research (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Frank House Research (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Frick Building Research (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Frick Fine Arts Building Research (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Fulton Building Research (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Gateway Center Research (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Golden Triangle General Research Including Fort Pitt Hotel, Liberty Center (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Grace Episcopal Church Research (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Granite Research (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Grant Building Research (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Grant Street Booklet by Steve Casey (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Gulf Research (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Heathside Cottage Research (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Heinz Chapel and Cathedral of Learning Research (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Heinz Factories Research (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Heinz Hall/Benedum Center Research (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Highland Park Research (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Hill District, Uptown, and the Bluff Research (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
      - Holy Rosary Church Research (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Homewood Research (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - IBM and Steelworkers Building Research (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Immaculate Heart of Mary Research (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Industrial Bank Research (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Introduction to the Golden Triangle – Old Plate Maps and Diagrams (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Isaly's Dairy Research (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - John Singer House Research (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Jones House Research (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Kaufmann's Research (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Kin's House Research (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Koppers Building Research (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Lemington School Research (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Liberty Avenue and Trump Skyscrapers Research (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Liberty Avenue, Bloomfield Research (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Liberty Avenue Lofts Research (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Liberty Avenue Old Research (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Liberty Center Research (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Lincoln – Larimer Fire Station Research (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Liverpool Street Research (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - 311 Lowenhill Street Research (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Lubetz Office Research (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Lutheran Church Research (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Magee Building Research (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Mary Schenley Fountain Research (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Mattress Factory Research (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Mellon Institute Research (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Mellon Square Research (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Mexican War Streets Research (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Monongahela and Duquesne Inclines Research (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Monongahela Valley Towns: Hazelwood, Rankin, Homestead, Braddock, Mckeesport, Trafford, Wilmerding Research (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
      - Motor Square Garden Research (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Municipal Courts Research (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - National Aviary Research (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - New Alcoa Research (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - North Side Research (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Oakland Introduction Research (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Oakland Square Research (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Old Allegheny Post Office and Children's Museum Research (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Oliver Building Research (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Oliver Plaza Research (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - One Mellon Bank Center Research (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Oratory/ Ryan Catholic Center Research (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Oxford Center Research (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Pittsburgh Athletic Association Research (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Park Building Research (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Penn Avenue Research (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Penn Station Research (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Phipps Conservatory Research (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Piatt Place Research (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Pittsburgh Metropolitan Statistical Area Research (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - PNC First Side Research (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Point Breeze, Wilkinsburg, Edgewood, Swissvale Research (Box 4, Folder 40-41)
      - PPG Place Research (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - The Priory Research (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Rampala House Research (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Ralph S. Meyer Plant Research (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Rebecca House/Jane Holmes Research (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Regional History Center Research (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Renaissance Pittsburgh Hotel Research (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Rhodes House Research (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Robinson and Chesterfield Street Research (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Rodef Shalom Research (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Ross Street Station Research (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Saint Anthony of Padua Shrine Research (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Saint John the Baptist Ukrainian Church Research (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Saint Michael's Cemetery Research (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Saint Paul's Cathedral Research (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Schenley Farms Research (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
      - Schenley Hotel/William Pitt Union Research (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Schenley Park Research (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Schenley Plaza Research (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Seventh Street and Sixth Street Research (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Shadyside Presbyterian Research (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Shadyside Research (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Sixteenth Street Bridge Research (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Sixth, Seventh, and Nineth Street Bridges Research (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Smithfield Street Bridge Research (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Smithfield Street Buildings Research (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Smithfield United Church of Christ and Harvard–Yale-Princeton Club Research (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Software Engineering Institute Research (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Soldiers and Sailors Memorial Research (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - South Side Research (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Spring Hill Research (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Squirrel Hill, Greenfield, Murdoch Farms Research (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Station Square Research (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - The Strip – Polish Hill, Lawrenceville, Bloomfield Research (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Subway Research (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Theater Square Research (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Triangle Building and Neighbors Research (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Trinity Cathedral Research (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - Union Trust Research (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Urban Room Research (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - USX Tower Research (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Warhol Museum Research (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Washington Landing Research (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Watson-Standard Building Research (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Westinghouse's Original Air Brake Factory Research (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - WQED Research (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Neighborhoods, 1986-1995
      - Allegheny Valley Towns in Pittsburgh, Oakmont, Natrona, New Kensington, and Sharpsburg Research (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - East Liberty, Highland Park, Homewood, Stanton Hills, Lincoln and Friendship in Pittsburgh Research (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
      - Epilogue Special Lists in Outer Pennsylvania Research (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Fifth Avenue and Street car suburbs of Pittsburgh Research (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
      - Golden Triangle in Pittsburgh Research (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Inland East area of Pittsburgh including Churchill, Penn Hills, Monroeville, and Plum Research (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Inland North Pittsburgh North Hills area of Fox Chapel. Evergreen, Millvale, Ross Township, and Swan Acres Research (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Inland South and Outflow of the Monongahela including Hazelwood, Bridgeville, Duquesne, South Hills, Mt. Lebanon, Washington, Crafton, Carnegie, Upper St. Claire Research (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
      - Lawrenceville, Bloomfield, Garfield area of Pittsburgh Research (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Maps of Neighborhoods (Box 61, Item 2-22)
      - Mon Valley Research (Box 6, Folder 18-19)
      - The North Side of Pittsburgh Research (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
      - Oakland Research (Box 7, Folder 3-7)
      - Ohio Valley and West End in Pittsburgh including Thornburg, Bellevue, Steuben, Avalon, Crafton, Ambridge, Aliquippa, and Mckees Rocks Research (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
      - Ohio Valley Research (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
      - Penn Avenue and Rail Road suburbs of Pittsburgh Research (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
      - Sewickley and Adjoining Pittsburgh Area Research (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - The South Side of Pittsburgh Research (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - The South Side of Pittsburgh Research (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
      - South, Southwest, and Southeast of Pittsburgh (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - The Strip and Polish Hill Pittsburgh Research (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Industry, 1986-1995
      - Adamson United Research (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Allegheny Airlines, Inc. Research (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Allegheny Ludlum Industries Research, 1970-1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Aluminum By Alcoa Research (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Architects in Pennsylvania Information (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Better Business Bureau Consumer Resource Book and Membership Roster, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Blaw-Knox Company Research (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Buildings by Pedagogs (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - The Changing Face of Pittsburgh Magazine, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Chemetron Research, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Coal Research (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Colt Industries Annual Report, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania Department of Environmental Resources Bureau of Topographical and Geological Survey Educational Booklets (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Corporations Review of Western Pennsylvania, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - CPI Company Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Cyclops Industries Research (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Dravo Industry Research (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Duquesne Light Company Research (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Dynamic Pittsburgh Booklet (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Equitable Builds A Gateway (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - An Eye for Architecture Booklet, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Food Industries Research (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Gas Research (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - The General Aviation Story, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - General Electric Investor Issue, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Hazelwood Coke Works of Jones & Laughlin (J&L) Steel Research (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Heinz Industry Research (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Historic and Architectural Survey of the Strip District, March, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - H.K. Porter Company Research (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Howard Fogg Pittsburgh and Lake Erie Art (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - The Industrial Directory Manufacturing Facilities in Allegheny County (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Joy Manufacturing Company Research (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Key to the Keystone State Pennsylvania, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Leadership Pittsburgh Profiles Alumni Directory, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Made in Pittsburgh Stamp (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Means of Presentation Research (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
      - Mesta Machine Company Research (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - MSA Safety and Health Products Report (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - National Register Blueprints (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Penn Southwest Association Booklet (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Penn Southwest Association Research (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Pittsburgh and Lake Erie Railroad Company Research (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Pittsburgh Ethnic Group Research (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Pittsburgh History and Landmarks Foundation 15 Year Report, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Pittsburgh Industries and Cultures Research (Box 9, Folder 20-22)
      - Pittsburgh Magazines (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - Pittsburgh Maps and Guides (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Pittsburgh Register of Historic Places Research, December 10, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Pittsburgh Resources and Bibliography (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - Pittsburgh Restaurant Guide (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Pittsburgh Steel Art Exhibits (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Pittsburgh Visual Elements and Bibliography (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - PPG Industries Research (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
      - Preliminary Criteria for Pittsburgh Register of Historic Places (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Railroad Research (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Reports of the Allegheny Conference on Community Development, 1977-1984 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Rockwell International Research (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Romancing in Tin Plate (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Scaife Company Research (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Spaceship Research (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Steel Research (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - A Survey of Historical Sources Relating to the Pennsylvania Main Line Canal in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, December 1983 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Things to do in Pittsburgh (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Union Mechling Research (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - United States Light Rail Transit Reconstruction UMTA Project, Environmental Impact Draft, July, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - United States Steel Research (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Wabco: American Standard Inc. of Westinghouse Research (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Wean United Company Research (Box 10, Folder 20-22)
      - White Consolidated Industries Research (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - The Whole Pittsburgh Catalog Investment Proposal, March, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Wilkinson Math Group Report, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Drafts and Publication
      - Neighborhoods for Living (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - Neighborhoods for Living (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Pittsburgh On Street Notes, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 2-4)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - The New Yorker Article, January 9th, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Book Shipping Information (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Publicity Photos (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Pittsburgh Marketing and Publicity, 1985-1988 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Front Matter Photos (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 1: Golden Triangle Photos (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 2: Oakland Photos (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 3: Southside Photos (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 4: Northside Photos (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 5: Penn Avenue (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 6: 5th Avenue (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Pittsburgh: An Urban Portrait Chapter 7: Around Pittsburgh and Chapter 8: Outside Pittsburgh (Box 11, Folder 17)